JASON NELSON

jasonnelson11@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jason-n-84778a124/ https://github.com/jasondamion https://jasondesigns.net

Summary

Full stack web developer continuously learning the new tech being applied in the technology field today. Experienced with excellent client and project management skills. Dedicated to building customer loyalty and promoting win-win results for the company and the client. Action-oriented with strong ability to communicate effectively with technology, executive, and business audiences.

Technology

Certifications: AWS Cloud Practitioner

Front-End: HTML5, BootStrap, CSS3, JQuery, Ajax, DOM Manipulation, Handlebars, Javascript, API's, React.JS, Angular 6, SASS, Wordpress, ASP.Net, TypeScript.

Back-End: Node.JS, Express.JS, MySQL, Java, MongoDB, Sequelize/Mongoose, Database Design, API Development Integration and Unit Testing, Travis CI, C#, JWT

Software: Github, Git Version Control, Firebase, Git Bash, Command Prompt, FTP Client, AWS Console/CLI/SDK

Projects

Daycare Manager | Node.js, MySQL | Github

Full Stack Developer

Single-page web app for managing my church daycare.

- Incorporates Express.Js to host a local server to render the code on the laptop..
- Dynamically renders features and components using Handlebar.js with Sequelize.
- Utilizes Bootstrap, CSS, and SQL gueries to retrieve the children and their timesheets.

Disaster Recovery Relief | Restful API's | Angular | Github

Full Stack Developer

An Angular powered web app used to hire local contractors to help with disaster relief.

- Contractors may signup to get paid for helping out after a disaster.
- Contractors may rent equipment to use during their time.
- The admin will be able to change prices, roles and approve timecards.

Heavenly Joy Events | Nodemailer | Cloudinary | <u>Github</u> | <u>Live</u>

Full Stack Developer

A Kids Venue web app for reserving parties.

- Able to build your own party and customize it.
- Gallery available to give you a feel for the party.
- Contact Page available for guestions.'

Professional Experience

Summitworks South Plainfield ,NJ September 2019-Current

Software Engineer

- Researching, designing, implementing and managing software programs.
- Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems analysts.
- Writing and implementing efficient code..
- Working with Database Developer to implement dynamic data in applications.
- Maintaining and upgrading existing systems.

Etomon New York, NY June 2019 - September

2019

Back-End Developer Intern

- Work with developers to implement back-end services, APIs, and internal tools.
- Debug issues and address performance bottlenecks.
- Integrate applications with databases and work with table structures and data querying.
- Implement unit tests.
- Read and produce technical documentation.

Domino's Pizza Dumont, NJ February 2019 - Current

Assistant Manager

- Coordinate daily customer service operations (e.g. sales processes, orders and payments)
- Monitor and maintain store inventory
- Handle complaints from customers
- Evaluate employee performance and identify hiring and training needs
- Supervise and motivate staff to perform their best

DOMINO'S PIZZA DUMONT, NJ March 2016 - February 2019

Customer Service Representative

- Responsible for daily operational duties
- Training of new staff and managers
- Direct management of inbound call and order taking
- In charge of customer grievance resolution
- Directed shift peak times during management absence
- Responsible for pizza preparation

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM
Rutgers University, Jersey City, NJ, United States

2018-2019

Bachelors in Computer Science University of The People, Online University, CA, United States

2019-Current